Owen Adrian

Professional software engineer with a 7-year streak of composing robust and intuitive web solutions. Experienced in Ruby on Rails, C#, and React, along with extreme programming practices, Agile, Kanban, and test-driven development.

Mesa, AZ · (816) 944-0745 · me@owen.codes · owen.codes

Technical Skills

- Languages: Ruby (Rails, Sinatra), JavaScript (React, Svelte, Express.js), C#
- Databases: PostgreSQL, SQLite, MongoDB
- Cloud Platforms: Azure (App Service, Kubernetes), AWS (EC2, S3)
- Tools: Git, Linux, Docker, Kubernetes, Heroku, CI/CD

Experience

Software Engineer

Syntreno

Aug 2023 - Present

- Building a Ruby on Rails application and API for managing, processing, and embedding documents for retrieval-augmented generation for GPT-4.
- Designing real-time virtual buyer personas in Unity for sales training.

Software Engineer, Web

Unity Technologies

Mar 2021 - Jun 2023

- Implemented SSO and data providers in a React front-end and ASP.NET backend for importing third-party annotations from Autodesk, Procore, and Jira.
- Spun off microservices for file transformation to speed up job runtime by 90%.
- Containerized a Ruby on Rails app for deployment by the US Army Corps of Engineers and to aid in the reconstruction of Tyndall Air Force Base.

Full Stack Developer VisualLive

Mar 2020 - Mar 2021

- Maintained a Ruby on Rails codebase, wrote unit tests with RSpec, implemented CI/CD with GitHub Actions, and managed infrastructure on Azure.
- Used Bootstrap in front-end refactoring to optimize mobile user experience.
- Advised non-technical teams and developed custom CRM (Bitrix24, Salesforce) integrations for clients and marketing and sales teams.

Web Developer, Founder

Order Coffee Online

Sep 2017 - Mar 2020

- Developed an online ordering system in Ruby on Rails that processed over \$500,000 in sales from 3 cafes and made the mornings of over 3,000 customers.
- Led shareholder meetings to plan conceptualization and commercialization,
 refine project goals with product feedback, and develop marketing strategies.

Education

Technology Solutions	Northland Career and Professional Studies	May 2018
High School Diploma	Liberty North High School	May 2018